French citizen, born 09/14/1976 +81 (0)80 4855 3456 sacockedey@gmail.com

### SALES DIRECTOR / BUSINESS UNIT MANAGER

Trilingual MBA graduate with 12 years of experience in Japan in the industry, business consulting and retail fields. Creative, adaptable, quality and goal-oriented professional with strong analytic, organizational and team-leading skills, and a proven understanding of successfully growing business internationally.

EDUCATION	
Master of Business Administration KENT STATE UNIVERSITY, OH, USA	1999
Rennes Business School Diploma ECOLE SUPERIEURE DE COMMERCE DE RENNES, FRANCE	1999
Bachelor of Arts in International Business BRITISH OPEN UNIVERSITY	1998

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2012/08 -TIME LAPSE JAPAN (Tokyo) - Owner & Founder

present Video content creation agency specialized in time lapse footage (www.timelapsejapan.com)

- Creation of premium stock footage as well as on-demand content
- Consulting and support services: technical advice, location scouting, etc.
- Footage used daily all over the world for TV commercials, documentaries, trade shows, websites, etc. by leading corporations, networks and creative agencies

### MEPHISTO JAPAN KK (Tokyo) - General Manager 2012/01 -2012/07

Mephisto is the largest French leather footwear company (2 800 employees worldwide)

- Full P&L responsibility lines (5.5M EUR turnover; 50 employees)
- Import, sales and promotion of the company's women's and men's shoe lines
- Distribution in 30+ shop-in-shops in major department stores (incl. Mitsukoshi-Isetan, Takashimaya and Daimaru groups), independent retailers (120+), and high-end catalogs
- Selection and purchasing of Japan seasonal collections (around 200 SKUs)
- Merchandising, visual merchandising, sales staff training
- Yearly promotion planning and implementation (fairs, events and collaborations with stores, family sales, etc.)
- Supervising of all administrative matters (legal, accounting, payroll etc.)

- Negotiated with department stores to develop new shops, bring existing ones back to profit, close unprofitable ones; convinced several former clients to start working with the brand again
- Recruited and trained collaborators to replace 75% of previous head office team on French HQ's instructions
- Forensic work to clarify the company's financial and legal situation (over 35M JPY unreconciled AR as of Jan. '12) and sue predecessor on HQ's instructions
- Prepared implementation of computers in shops to gain access to stock and sales data, in order to enable trend analysis, merchandising activity, and reduce lost sales
- Proposals to alleviate recurring large unsold inventory issue (over 9 months as of Jan. '12) such as outlet stores, private flash internet sales, multi-brand family sales, etc.
- Proposals to increase sales and profitability such as introducing retail ERP solution, barcode scanning capacity, warehouse outsourcing, in-house accounting & payroll, etc.

### 2006/10 -SERAC JAPAN (Tokyo) - Representative Director

Serac Group is the leading French filling and capping machinery manufacturer for liquid products (80M euros annual turnover, 420 employees, 5 factories worldwide)

- Japanese branch in charge of the sale, installation and servicing of the group's equipment in Japan (2M EUR average turnover; 7 employees)
- Directly responsible for sales including prospection and technical presentations
- Overseeing of the relationships with sales agents and service subcontractors
- Catering to major beverage companies (Coca Cola, Nestle, Otsuka Seiyaku, Suntory...) mainly in the highly technical aseptic filling field
- Projects usually up to several millions euros

### 2011/12

### Main Achievements:

- Doubled the turnover on the first year through implementation of a full-scale local customer service, launching new maintenance products, and tapping into unexploited business opportunities for upgrades on existing equipment
- Tripled turnover on the 3<sup>rd</sup> year & achieved largest turnover since establishment in 1999
- Improved customer satisfaction and doubled repeat orders through better service
- Developed successful interpersonal relationships with clients' decision makers
- Identified numerous local best practices and got them incorporated into the worldwide technical standard through close relationship with R&D and manufacturing departments
- Pre-sale regional expert for key-account aseptic technology customers (regular trips to South Korea, Indonesia, China)
- Transformed representative office into branch to reduce fiscal risk

## 2001/09 - FRENCH EMBASSY IN JAPAN – ECONOMIC DEPARTMENT (Tokyo) The network of Economic Departments offers paid market entry core

The network of Economic Departments offers paid market entry consulting services to French companies worldwide as well as liaison between French and local administrations for economic and business-related matters

### 2003 - 2006 Commercial Attaché in charge of the Legal Affairs and Services Industry Department

- Advised over 600 French companies regarding all aspects of setting-up and conducting a business in Japan (legal, tax, HR, intellectual property issues as well as marketing strategy and business practices)
- Liaison with high-ranking officials (Fair Trade Commission, IP authorities, Supreme Court, Japan Post, Finance Ministry...) for bilateral benchmarking, cooperation, and treaty negotiation (social security and tax) purposes
- Intellectual Property expert in Japan for the French Ministry of Economy and Finance

### 2001 - 2003 Head of the ISO 9001:2000 Quality Management team

- Internal procedures, staff training, internal audit. 3 successful audits in 3 years
- Over 98% measured overall customer satisfaction

### 2001 - 2003 Deputy Commercial Attaché in charge of the Consumer Goods Department

- Advice and support to over 500 French companies and professional organizations (fashion, cosmetics, interior goods, entertainment): market entry strategy, clients and distributors prospection, fairs and promotional events organization, market research
- Over 20 papers and studies published about Japanese market and regulations
- Managed a team of 5 assistants

# 2000/04 - ERAMET JAPAN (Tokyo) - Marketing Manager (CSNE / "French national service as a trainee in a corporate environment")

Leading French integrated mining and metallurgy group producing non-ferrous metals and high-performance special steels (2009 turnover: 2.7 billion EUR; 15,000 employees)

- Market intelligence for nickel, manganese and high-speed steels
- Assisted senior sales representatives in negotiations of multimillion USD ore supply contracts to major Japanese steel manufacturers
- Monthly and quarterly reporting to the French head office

# 1999/12 - CARREFOUR MALAYSIA (Kuala Lumpur) - Assistant Sourcing Manager (internship) 2000/02 Sourcing office of the world's second largest retailer.

- Launch of new products of the Carrefour brand « Lowest Prices »: opportunity analysis, suppliers selection, choice of brand name and packaging, promotion planning. Products launched: mineral water, shampoo, chocolate powder
- participated to preparations for the opening of the 6th store in Malaysia

### **LANGUAGES**

English (fluent; TOEFL 623 points); Japanese (fluent; JLPT 2); French (mother tongue).

### PERSONAL INTERESTS AND PUBLICATIONS

- Fine arts photography, video production: www.samuelcockedey.com
- Travel and trekking (Everest Base Camp, 18 200 ft/5 500 m, Dec. 2008)
- « Setting up a Business in Japan » (2004); « Commercial Contracts in Japan » (2005), Editions Ubifrance